Ajoy Kumar Barman 🕡 Featured

Devops Engineer seeking roles in Software Development, Application
Programming, System Analysis, Technical Architecture, Cloud Computing, Release
Management, Cloud Computing, Project Management, Client
Management, HTML, CSS, Maven, Jenkins, JIRA, Eclipse



Current Designation: Devops Engineer Total Experience: 14 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: IBM India Pvt. Limited Notice Period: 3 Months

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Electrical]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Hyderabad, Pune Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Devops Engineer, Software Developer, Software Development, Application Programming, System

Analysis, Technical Architecture, Cloud Computing, Release Management, Cloud Computing, Project Management, Client

Management, HTML, CSS, Maven, Jenkins, JIRA, Eclipse

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Summary

Total 14 years of IT Experience and 3 Years in DevOps, Build & Release Engineering and automation experience in leading IT companies

Experience as a Lead Release Engineer and DevOps Consultant working in various continuous integration tools like Jenkins and Bamboo.

Experienced in version control tools like SVN, BitBucket and GIT.

Experienced in implementing code quality tools as SonarQube.

Clear understanding of the software development life cycle: from requirement collection to client delivery

Proficiency in Integrated Development Environment like Eclipse

Working knowledge in servers like Tomcat, WebSphere and jboss

Microservices deployment experience using docker and Kubernetes.

Familiar with ticketing tools like HP - Quality Centre and Service Now, Remedy, Triole, Manage Now, HPALM, Jira.

Domain Knowledge in Airline, Travel & Hospitality, Banking and Retail Industry, Healthcare, Pharmacy, Chemical.

Work Experience

IBM India Pvt. Limited as Devops Engineer

May 2008 to Till Date

Project Details Anthem Inc (May 2020- Present)

IPCC Canada (February2020 to May2020)

Suncore Energy (November2019 to February2020)

Lufthansa Airlines (August2018 to October2019)

IKEA (June2017 to August2018)

Shop Direct NCE (December2016 to June2017)

Vodafone Netherland (August2014 to December2016)

Cocacola, Seadrill (August2012 to August2014)

Koninklijke Friesland foods nv (November 2011 to August2012)

IGA (May2008 to November 2011)

Roles and Responsibility

Designing and deployment processes

Handle build/Release of software and Automate build tasks using Shell scripts

Managing build infrastructure and build environments

Co-ordination with Environment team to ensure the delivered artifacts are deployed successfully

Create Vagrant VM and Setting for deployment.

Confluence and Jira Administrator

Set up of Devops tools and Frameworks

End to End Sanity and Smoke test

On-calls and support for weekend or extended hour depends on client requirement.

Overall environment ownership

Installed Certificates in Different servers

Service now ticket resolution

User access and Group creation

Weekly back up for Different Devops tool

Preparing new test environment.

Log and application monitoring trough Devops tool.

Coordinate with other vendors and plan according to different level of Data Level Agreement

Responsible to plan Production Go Live by Phase by Phase

Release Level Planning and Change Structure Process Establishment

VDI Administration

Handling Abinitio License Management

Managing Back-ups daily and restoring them when needed.

Key Highlights

Devops practices implementation

Fully Automated Deployments in different environments (Dev, SIT, UAT, INT, PROD)

Release Management

Delivered multiple releases to production.

Innovation and tool development

Multiple client and IBM awards and Bluepoints

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electrical) from West Bengal University Of Technology in 2007

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
Windows XP, Windows 7			
Windows10, Linux/Unix			
Shell Scripting			
Oracle 10g, Oracle 11g			
Jenkins, Bamboo			
DOCKER			
Eclipse			
HTML			
MAVEN			
SVN, Git, Bitbucket			
SOAP UI, JIRA, RTC			
Sonar Qube, Nexus, Jfrog			

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak	
English	Expert				

1/22/2021 https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=1fbb24121e87a5cee6afda25110f9cd40d5858574a150e450117425c5c0...

Hindi	Expert
Bengali	Expert

Affirmative Action

Category: General

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time